ABIODUN OLONADE

36 Transit village 2, Adetokunbo Ademola Street, Victoria island, Lagos state <u>emmanuel olonade@yahoo.com</u> (+234)-80-3282-7281 / (+234)-70-1510-9571 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abiodun-emmanuel

OBJECTIVE

Graduate of Electronics and Electrical Engineering with a major in Communication engineering. Highly organized and resourceful entry-level front-end developer with a superb work ethic, engineering and coding background. Seeking to leverage my 5+ years' programming skills as a Junior Software Engineer.

I am a passionate front-end web developer with 3years+ of learning experience using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and React JS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for web apps.

SKILLS

Database and Programming Languages

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Modern JavaScript, React JS, Next JS, Redux, Material UI, Debugging, Git/GitHub

Software Tools

Microsoft Word, Excel and Power point.
WordPress.

Communication and Interpersonal

Effective communicator Decision-maker and Problem solver Critical and Analytical Thinking Eager to learn

EDUCATION

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology | Bachelor of Technology

Ogbomoso, Oyo State | **11.2015** – **12.2021**

- Major in Electronics and Electrical Engineering
- Coursework: Communication Engineering
- Member of Nigeria society of engineers (Graduate member)
- Grade: Second Class Upper

Educational legacy college | *High School*

Ibadan, Oyo State | **09.2007 – 08.2013**

- Science Department
- West African Senior School Certificate Examination (WASSCE) certified
- National Examination Council (NECO) certified

PROJECTS

GitHub Repository https://github.com/SlimPapii

Personal Portfolio

https://abiodun-olonade.vercel.app/

Project: Responsive Website Design

Role: Developer

Technologies: HTML and CSS

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the https://transportservices.netlify.app using HTML and CSS only in order to showcase my understanding of responsive designs.

Project: Login Page Authentication

Role: Developer

Technologies: HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the https://loginpageauth.netlify.app/ using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I

made use of local storage to save the details of the user.

Project: Ode to Zainab - NonProfit

Role: Lead Developer

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the https://ode-to-zainab.vercel.app/ using React JS also implemented

navigation using React Router.

More projects are available on my repository, link is above

RELATED EXPERIENCE

BEESTECH | Volunteer

Ibadan, Oyo State | **02.2020 – Present**

- Created more than 5 web application with HTML and CSS3
- Used CSS media queries/Bootstrap to design multiple responsive web apps
- Created, maintained, and enforced front-end code and documentation standards (readable codes)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

NoemDek Limited | *IT/Procurement Analyst*

Ikoyi, Lagos | **08.2022** – **Present**

- Determining supply needs and researching potential suppliers.
- Acting as a liaison and communicating pricing and performance needs to vendors and suppliers.
- Sourcing suppliers and testing product samples.
- Documenting the features and benefits of products and services.
- Preparing cost-benefit analysis reports for review by managers.
- Negotiating favorable procurement contracts with selected vendors and suppliers.
- Documenting processes and generating monthly supply cost reports.
- Monitoring the company's demand for products to avoid supply shortages.
- Keeping abreast of vendor and supplier-related activities in the industry.

HUAWEI TECHNOLOGY.CO.NIG LTD | *INTERN*

Lekki-epe, Lagos | **08.2020 - 12.2020**

Airtel managed service telecommunication engineer

- Effectively & efficiently maintaining the BTS & Access Radio Network; ensuring the overall network availability meets the pre-set targets as laid out by the management, taking into cognizance the platinum, gold, silver & bronze sites are all placed in order of Priorities.
- Efficient resolution of all Network Faults (Power outages, Transmission Access Radio & BTS failures) ensuring that the average downtime of 6 hours for MTTR is maintained.
- Troubleshooting and configuration of Node B on both ATM and IP RAN link.
- Proffer solutions to repetitive BSS network problems affecting network quality and availability on all BSS Platform as assigned.
- Installation & Maintenance of the BTS and transmission equipment.
- Site configuration in accordance with Installation Specifications.

SIR KAY Electrical works | *INTERN*

Ibadan,Oyo State | **05.2016** – **01.2017**

Surface and conduit wiring

INTERESTS

Travel enthusiast with keen interest in other cultures, coding, meeting new faces, listening to Music and also I enjoy watching football matches.

VOLUNTEERS

I was a member of Transformation Academy group, where I take fresh year students Mathematics and I also take the year two students Engineering Analysis. This has helped me to build confidence to approach a large crowd and convince them to listen and buy into my ideas.

REFERENCES

AVAILABLE ON REQUEST.